宇宙…
The universe…
空间和物质的无限延伸
a vast expanse of space and matter.
包含着我们所见及所知的一切
It includes all that we see, and all that we know.
从一开始
Since the beginning of time,
我们就想知道它从何而来
we have wondered how it came to be.
一场壮丽的精心安排？
A gloriously orchestrated plan?
还是一系列巧合？
A chance series of events?
还是什么不能更蠢的理由？
Or something much, much dumber?
噫！
Eee!
《冰川时代5：星际碰撞》
今天是美好的一天…
It's a beautiful day out here on the ice…
父女齐聚冰上
as father meets daughter.
参加一场别开生面的冰球争霸赛
in a quest for hockey supremacy.
选手是桃子对曼尼
It's Peaches meets Manny.
猛犸象对猛犸象
Mammoth meets mammoth.
猛长牙对猛长牙
Mano a mano.
猛大象对猛小象
Meema me moo-ma.
猛爸爸对猛女儿
Mama may mee-mee.
你们俩能不能安静点？
Will you two quit it?
猛好吧
M-okay.
猛小气鬼
Meanie.
进击的猛犸象带着球长驱直入
The blazing mammoth takes it on the breakaway.
从没有一位球员能如此坚强 如此优雅
There's never been a player so tough, so graceful.
如此渴望得分
So desperate to score.
他假装向右 假装向左
He fakes right. He fakes left.
他假装知道怎么玩曲棍球
He fakes knowing how to play.
嗯？怎么啦？
Huh? What's wrong?
丢什么东西啦？
Lose something?
嘿 我闻到哪里来的臭味？是曼尼！
Hey, what's that stink I smell out there? It's Manny!
嘿 嘿 是曼尼！
Hey, hey. It's Manny!
吼！你太臭啦！
Whoo! You stink!
好吧 小毛球 让我看看你的能耐
Okay, Fuzzball. Let's see what you got.
这可是你自找的
You asked for it.
太棒了！她又进球啦！又进啦！
Yes! She dominates! Again.
哦 拜托 我对你可是很温柔的
Oh, please. I went easy on you.
这叫好的育儿方式
It's called good parenting.
得了吧 面对现实吧
Yeah, right. Face it.
现在我才是冰上王者
I rule the ice now.
你口气倒不小啊 小高手
Oh, you talk a big game, hotshot.
好吧 三局两胜怎么样？
All right, how about best of three?
哦吼！触地得分！
Whoo-hoo! Yes! Touchdown!
等下 不对 不是触地得分 那是什么？
Wait, no, that's not right. Not touchdown. What is it?
呃 一杆进洞！喔！
Uh, hole-in-one! Whoo!
朱利安！哇哦！
Julian! Whoa!
抱歉
Ow! Sorry.
亲爱的 我刚刚得分了！你看到了吗？
Honey, I scored! Did you see me?
看到啦！你简直棒呆了
Yeah! And you were amazing. Whoa! Whoa!
小心！
Careful!
哦 这冰可太滑了
Oh, the ice is really icy.
简直超级过度滑溜溜
It's like super-sized, extra value icy.
不过我滑得更好了 对吧？
But I'm getting better, right?
哇哦！
Whoa!
好吧 我们… 等下再玩儿
Okay, we'll play… later.
她又把你打得屁滚尿流了？
So, she whupped your butt again, huh?
而且你这屁股的块头
And with a butt that size,
真是够你翻滚的
that's a whole lot of whuppin'.
没人被打得屁滚尿流 也没人翻滚
Nobody was whupped. There was no whupping.
这只是一个慈祥的父亲
It's just a loving father.
在跟她唯一的女儿讨论战术
sharing some strategy with his only daughter.
我还不知道烂水平也能称为战术
Didn't know sucking was a strategy.
好了 轮到我们了
Okay, it's our turn.
让他们看看好球该怎么打！
Let's show them how it's done!
你要输惨了 嗯？
You're going down, eh?
哒哒嗒嗒！
Ta-ta-da-da!
给你的 我亲爱的岳母
For you, my mom-in-law-to-be.
金盏花！
Buttercups!
来自大自然的阳光
Nature's sunshine.
阳光本来不就属于大自然的吗？
Isn't sunshine nature's sunshine?
谢谢！朱利安
Aw! Thank you, Julian.
已经很久没人送过我花了
It's been so long since anyone's given me flowers.
但是你要娶的是我们的女儿
But you're marrying our daughter.
不用总是给我们带礼物
You don't have to keep bringing us presents.
但我觉得很开心啊
But it makes me happy.
还有给你的 我的导师 偶像 最崇敬的猛犸象…
And for you, my guru, my rock, my main mammoth…
我要把最好的礼物给你
To you, I give the greatest gift of all.
等等 你要干嘛？
Wait. What are you doing?
来吧 我的老丈人 来个拥抱
Come on, Bro-Dad. Bring it in.
我能感受到你的心跳
I can feel your heart beating.
好了 够了
Okay. That's enough of that.
你最好习惯习惯
You better get used to it.
他们将来可是要住我们隔壁的
They'll be living right next door.
来吧 朱利安 要走吗？
Come on, Julian. Wanna go?
等下 你能不能帮帮我那件事？
Actually, weren't you gonna help me with the thing?
哦！没错 那件事
Oh! Right. The thing.
要去做那件事
Gotta do the thing.
我可以做那件事
I can do the thing.
不！
No!
这是女孩子之间的事
It's a girl thing.
嘿！你们干嘛不去做点男孩子之间的事？
Hey! Why don't you go do a guy thing?
你已经很久
You know, you don't spend.
没跟你的朋友们好好玩了
nearly enough time with your friends.
- 没有吗？- 我们等会儿再见
- I don't? - I'll see you later.
在这个特殊的日子
On this special day.
呃… 好吧
Uh… Okay.
你跟他们说了我们的决定了吗？
Have you told them about our decision yet?
还没 我想等个合适的时机
No. I'm waiting for the right time.
来吧 罗密欧 跟我走
Come on, Romeo. Walk with me.
我准备去看看蝴蝶
I'm gonna watch some butterflies.
破茧而出
come out of their cocoons.
- 哇哦！真的吗？- 假的
- Whoa! Really? - No.
拜拜 宝贝儿
Goodbye, sweetie.
哦！我记得以前我跟曼尼也是这样的
Aw! I remember when Manny and I used to be like that.
我不是！爱上他们 离开他们
Not me! Love them and leave them,
然后带走一半的财产
and take half of everything.
这就是我的准则
That's my motto.
亲爱的 曾经有无数女人妄想…
Mi amor, so many ladies have tried and failed…
给我希德这匹野马安上缰绳
to strap a saddle on Sid the stallion.
但我只想和你分享我的一切
But I want to share everything with you.
你就是我身上的跳蚤
You're the wind beneath my fleas,
眼里的水藻
the algae of my eye.
你愿意和我共度余生吗？
Will you be my mate for life?
- 希德？- 嗯？
- Sidney? - Mmm?
希德 你在哪儿？
Sidney, where are you?
弗朗辛
Francine.
我想问你…
I need to ask…
我想问你一件事
I need to ask you something.
你愿意嫁…
Will you marry…
希德 我要就此打断你
Sid, I'm gonna stop you right there.
我要和你分手
I'm breaking up with you.
什么？但我都计划好我们的未来了！
What? But I planned our whole future!
我们的婚礼
Our wedding.
我们的孩子
Our kids.
妈咪
Mommy.
我们的墓地
Our burial plots.
你好吗？
How you doing?
我还请了个乐队
I even hired a band.
嘿！
Hey!
不不不 现在不行！
No, no. Not yet!
你疯了吗？我们才约会了一次
Are you crazy? We've only had one date.
而且只持续了14分钟！
It lasted 14 minutes!
没错 但我觉得像过了20分钟
Yes, but it felt like 20.
不行！戒指？
I can't! A ring?
我喜欢戒指 但是不能嫁给你
I mean, I like the ring, but no.
不行 你太粘人了
I can't. You're too clingy.
我哪里粘人了？
How is this clingy?
而且顺便说下
And by the way,
你跟照片上长得一点都不像
you look nothing like your profile picture.
弗朗辛 你得开始和
Francine, you gotta start dating.
其他物种约会了
outside of your species.
小辛辛 我们再好好谈谈 是因为那个比基尼吗？
Franny, we can work this out. Is this about the bikini? Ow!
我也不知道那是毒藤做的啊
I didn't know it was poison ivy.
哦！糟了
Oh! Uh-oh.
小辛辛 小辛辛 救命啊！
Franny. Franny, help!
有人吗
Somebody.
是我的眼睛受伤了…
Is it the eyes that hurt…
还是我的灵魂？
or my soul?
喔！
Ow!
一定是我的眼睛
Definitely the eyes.
啊 女人啊！
Ah, women!
没错 女人啊
Yeah, women.
她们怎么了？
What about them?
我不理解她们
I don't get 'em.
比如说 艾丽 和她在一起的生活非常棒
Like, Ellie. Life's great with her.
没有惊喜 没有变化
There's no surprises. Nothing ever changes.
但是今天 她傻笑了
But then today, she giggled.
希拉会傻笑吗？
Does Shira ever just giggle?
求你别吃我！
Please don't eat me!
呃… 希拉不是那种爱傻笑的虎
Uh… Shira's not a big giggler.
好吧 艾丽傻笑了
Well, Ellie giggled.
然后她就开始来回摇摆
And then she wiggled.
「嘻嘻嘻嘻」 砰！
"Tee hee hee hee." Boom!
别再这么做
Don't ever do that again.
我真不知道为什么她表现得这么奇怪
I have no idea why she's acting so weird.
女人啊
Women.
有人吗？
Hello?
说到奇怪
And speaking of weird.
这里有人吗？哦！
Anybody there? Oh!
马可？波罗？
Marco? Polo?
哦 嗨 曼尼
Oh, hi, Manny.
呃！口气这么大你该刷刷牙了
Ew! Your breath is awful.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
没什么 一切安好
Oh, nothing. Everything's great.
棒呆 无比美妙
Fabulous. Zippity-dippity.
好吧 我猜猜 她把你甩了
Okay, let me guess. She dumped you.
我做错了什么？
What is wrong with me?
每个人都有另一半
Everybody has somebody.
而我却只有我年轻俊秀的容颜
And all I've got is my boyish good looks.
和这个墨西哥流浪乐队
and this mariachi band.
哦！好痒！
Oh! So itchy!
来吧 带你去洗洗干净
Come on. Let's get you cleaned up.
我想要的不过是真爱
All I wanted is true love.
这要求过分吗？
Is that too much to ask?
为什么如此安静？
Why is it so quiet?
因为世界都在为我默哀
Because the world is mourning my loss.
艾丽？
Ellie?
桃子？
Peaches?
大家都去哪儿了？
Where is everyone?
惊喜！
Surprise!
嗒哒！
Ta-da!
结婚纪念日快乐 亲爱的！
Happy Anniversary, honey!
纪念日？
Anniversary?
哦 不 她们说的是这件事
Oh, no. That's the thing.
好了！现在轮到你了 我的老丈人！
Okay! Now it's your turn, Bro-Dad!
没错！我们想看看你给艾丽准备了什么
Yeah! We wanna see what you got Ellie.
曼尼！
Manny!
曼尼！曼尼！曼尼！
Manny! Manny! Manny!
曼尼！
Manny!
嘿 嘿 好了
Hey, hey. Right.
呃…
Uh…
再向艾丽求婚一次怎么样？
How about another hand for Ellie?
很好
Yeah.
哦
Oh.
他忘了！
He forgot!
我真为艾丽难过
I feel so bad for Ellie.
艾丽 我… 呃…
Ellie, I… Uh…
他没忘
He didn't forget.
曼尼真的好爱她！
That's how big Manny's love is for her!
这烟火真够及时的
Nice save with the light show.
等等 你放的？那是谁放的？
Wait, you didn't do this? Then who did?
哦 曼尼
Oh, Manny.
我真担心你忘了
I was so afraid you'd forgotten.
但是你竟然为我点亮整片天空？
But you lit up the sky for me?
你是怎么做到的？
How'd you do it?
呃 那个…
Uh, well…
魔术师从不揭开他的奥秘
A magician never reveals his secrets.
谢谢
Thank you.
我经常在这儿想象我们未来的宝宝
I keep picturing our own kid in there.
他一定是最棒的
He'd be the best one.
我觉得你说的是 「她」
I think you meant "she."
他
He.
都可以吧 不说这个了 迪亚哥
Either way, we've been over this, Diego.
小孩子都害怕我们
Kids are afraid of us.
没错 但是为什么呢？
Yeah, but why?
他们要吃了我们吗？
Are they gonna eat us?
嗨 孩子们！
Hi, kids!
这次我甚至都微笑了
I even smiled this time.
哇哦 爸爸
Wow, Dad.
这真是最好的礼物
Best present ever.
先生 你简直是婚姻中的模范
You, sir, are an education in marital excellence.
我们走了之后会很想念你们的
I'm really gonna miss you guys when we leave.
呃 其实 我还没有告诉他们
Um, actually, I haven't told them yet.
这样啊
Oh.
惊喜！
Surprise!
你们要走了？
You're leaving?
我以为你们头几年
I thought you guys were gonna live with us.
都会和我们住在一起
the first couple of years.
我知道 但是朱利安和我
I know. But Julian and I.
想要出去闯荡一阵子
kind of want to roam for a while.
- 闯荡？- 没错！
- Roam? - Yeah!
旅行 探险 到处去玩儿
Travel, explore, just go wherever.
没有计划就是最好的计划 这就是我的人生哲学
No plan is the best plan. That's my philosophy.
来点儿点心？
Hors d'oeuvres?
这不是什么计划 也不是什么哲学…
That's not a plan, or a philosophy…
也很不安全
or very safe.
老爸 我们还年轻
Dad, we're young.
等我们到了你和老妈一样喜欢平淡的年纪
We can worry about being safe when we're old and boring.
再来讨论安全问题吧
Like you and Mom.
- 我们觉得我们应该就… - 抱歉！
- I think we should just… - Excuse me!
这是家庭会议
This is a family discussion.
难道我不是其中一份子吗？
But aren't I part of your family?
不 现在还不是
Not yet, you're not.
你觉得那个有什么问题吗？
Does that look like a problem to you?
一个火球径直朝我们飞来？
A ball of fire heading directly towards us?
哪有什么问题？
Why would that be a problem?
要是你跌到沟里失去记忆怎么办？
What if you fall in a ditch and get amnesia?
到时候怎么办？
What then, huh?
曼尼 我们有麻烦了
Manny, we have a problem.
现在不是时候 我自己的麻烦都没解决
Not now. I have a problem.
我说的这个麻烦比较严重
This one's a little bigger.
- 我可不觉得 - 曼尼！
- I don't think so. - Manny!
怎么了？
What?
曼尼 你怎么了？
Manny?
好了 宴会结束了 各位
Uh, okay. Party's over, everybody.
晚安 大家都散了吧！
Have a good night. And leave right now!
你在说什么？宴会才刚刚开始
What are you talking about? The party just got started.
对
Yeah.
可是我有点困了
Just getting kind of sleepy.
大家都走吧 卧倒 最好找个地方躲起来！
Everyone should go. And duck. Possibly cover!
你这是怎么了？
Hey, what's gotten into you?
看！又来了好多！
Look! There's more coming!
流星雨！
Meteor shower!
流星？
Meteor?
浴？
Shower?
曼尼的爱要害死我们了！
Manny's love is killing us!
我猜这些都是你为我准备的惊喜？
I suppose this is all part of your magic show for me?
巴拉拉能量？
Abracadabra?
你们能待会再讨论这事吗？
Can you guys deal with this later?
快点 我们得找个地方躲起来
Come on. We need to take cover.
矮油！看我的火球！
Whoo-hoo! I'm on fire!
矮油！我也有！我们是酷鼠兄弟！
Whoo-hoo-hoo! Me too! We're smoking hot, baby!
来了！
Incoming!
这两家伙是我们的！
Those are ours!
你们没事吧？数数我有几根象牙？
Are you okay? How many tusks do you see?
树
Tree.
三个？
Three?
不！小心树！
No! Tree!
各就各位 跳！
Everybody, jump!
这有个洞穴！快进去！
The cave! Get inside!
快点！快点！
Move! Move!
没事了 宝贝 爸爸在…
It's okay, sweetheart. Daddy's…
好像情况好转了
Hey, it sounds like it's slowing down.
对 我确定一切都结束了
Yup, it's definitely over.
除了这个
Except for that one.
或许我们应该考虑
We might wanna think.
到地下住一段时间
about moving underground for a while.
瞧啊！我弄到了一个蛋
Look at that! I got an egg.
你弄到过几个蛋呢 小弟？
How many eggs did you poach, little brother?
我们必须得偷别人的蛋吗？
Do we have to steal other creatures' eggs?
难道我们就不能就吃素食？
I mean, couldn't we just go vegan?
当然 我们可以吃素食
Sure, we could eat vegans.
儿子 有时候我都怀疑
Son, sometimes I wonder.
你不是我们亲生的
how you snuck into this family.
∮ 费加罗 费加罗 ∮
∮ Figaro, Figaro ∮
∮ 费加罗 费加罗 费加罗 ∮
∮ Figaro, Figaro, Figaro ∮
等我一分钟 我得涂点肥皂洗洗干净
With you in a minute. I'll have to rinse and repeat.
那只黄鼠狼真让人扫兴
That weasel is such a buzzkill.
走吧 孩子们
Let's go, kids.
别担心 女士
Don't worry, ma'am.
我会帮你找回你的蛋蛋的
I'll catch the crew that poached your egg.
哥真是一语双关啊！
It's a pun!
我的机智之眼在眼罩下眨了眨
I'm winking under the eye patch.
∮ 一位母亲正因失去孩子悲痛欲绝 ∮
∮ A mother is crying a damsel in distress ∮
∮ 要说窃贼们造成这样的混乱 ∮
∮ Foreboding intruders have made such a mess ∮
∮ 对我来说就是不尊重 ∮
∮ What I detect is a lack of respect ∮
∮ 我是这个迷失世界的小小守护者 ∮
∮ For all that is precious and dear ∮
∮ 守护一切宝贝 ∮
∮ I am the pint-sized protector of this lost world ∮
不过我的小伙伴们都叫我巴克
But my friends call me Buck.
干得不错 伙计们
Well played, guys.
∮ 我可警告你们 这里不欢迎欺凌 ∮
∮ I have a message, bullies not welcome ∮
∮ 把你们所盗之物物归原主 ∮
∮ Return what you've stolen ∮
∮ 打哪来 回哪去 ∮
∮ Go back where you came from ∮
∮ 你知道我功夫了得 别做无谓的挣扎 ∮
∮ You know I'm greater, so don't be a hater ∮
∮ 你魔高一尺 我道高一丈 ∮
∮ You may be Jurassic, but I am fantastic ∮
∮ 费加罗 费加罗 费加罗 费加罗 费加罗 费加罗 ∮
∮ Figaro, Figaro, Figaro, Figaro, Figaro, Figaro ∮
∮ 费加罗 ∮
∮ Figaro ∮
这尾音超棒
Oh, love that bit.
∮ 奔跑 攀爬 旋转 微笑 ∮
∮ Running and climbing And spinning and grinning ∮
∮ 疾奔 猛冲 闪避 ∮
∮ And dashing and diving and dodging ∮
∮ 滑行 滑翔 努力生存 ∮
∮ And sliding and gliding and staying alive ∮
∮ 还有一些事儿 ∮
∮ And these are a few of the things ∮
∮ 我要在午餐之前搞定 ∮
∮ That I do before lunch ∮
∮ 不怕危险 不畏死亡 ∮
∮ Death defying Danger denying ∮
看 我在飞
Look, I'm flying.
∮ 或许你会觉得我疯了 可是人生不能重来 ∮
∮ You might think I'm mad. But, hey, you only live once ∮
∮ 无需感谢我 ∮
∮ No need to thank me ∮
∮ 但若你坚持 我也不会拒绝 ∮
∮ But if you insist, I won't resist ∮
谁身上那么臭？
Who smells like fish?
都坐坐好！
Huh? Hold on to your butts!
∮ 下 ∮
∮ Class ∮
∮ 课！∮
∮ Dismissed ∮
好蛋
Good egg.
给你 女士
Here you are, my lady.
快走！我去把他们引开
Go! I'll lead them away.
刚才多有意思啊！
Oh, that was fun!
下周同一时间同一地点我们再来？
Same time, same place, next week?
再见！
Toodles!
恭喜你 黄鼠狼
Congratulations, weasel.
你的死期到了
You just signed your death warrant.
黄鼠狼式谢幕
Weaseled my way out of that one.
那些闪闪发光的是什么？
Hmm. What's all that flash and dazzle about?
是谁在深林里放这么块石头？
Who puts a rock in the middle of the jungle?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
有人吗？
Hello?
上来了！
Yeah!
你们好啊 哺乳动物们
Oh! Hello, mammals.
你好啊 巴克！
Hi, Buck!
嗨
Hi.
再见 巴克！
Bye, Buck!
帮我一下
Um, a little help.
正中脾脏！
Right on the spleen!
这货虽然没什么用处 可还是很疼
Utterly useless, but totally hurts.
巴克老兄 欢迎回来
Hey, Buck. Welcome back, buddy.
等下 这只麻花状生物就是恐龙克星？
Wait. This half-a-snack is the dinosaur whisperer?
而且还是一名专业舞蹈家
And expert salsa dancer.
虽然我少了只眼睛 但是我有一口好牙
I have one eye but all my original teeth.
你要数数吗？
Would you like to count them? Ah…
不 谢了
No, thank you.
这位姑娘一定就是油桃了
And this must be Nectarine.
我叫… 桃子
Um… Peaches.
是一个意思啦 亲爱的
Semantics, my dear.
很荣幸能见到你
I am deeply honored.
这眼罩真不错 痞气十足
Sweet eye patch. Very gangsta.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我喜欢这孩子 - 巴克
- I like this kid. - Buck.
你在这里干嘛？
Whoa! What are you doing here?
我… 什么？
Well, I… What?
我在努力！
I'm trying!
可是你要怎么告诉别人他们完蛋了？
But how do you tell someone they're doomed?
他被难住了
He's stumped.
我们并不是完蛋了 巴克
We're not doomed, Buck.
那只是一场流星雨 现在已经结束了
It was just a meteor shower, and the show's over.
相反 老伙计
Oh, quite the contrary, old chap.
这只是开始
It's just beginning.
我找到了一则预言
You see, I found a prophecy.
停一停好吗？
Do you mind?
兄弟 他真是扫兴大王 不觉得吗？
Boy, he really sucks the fun out of everything. Doesn't he?
扫兴大王！
Fun sucker!
我把这个碑从头到尾的读了一遍
I read this tablet front to back.
上面的故事非常让人不安
And the story it tells is very disturbing.
差不多每隔一亿年
Every hundred million years or so,
这世界就会发生一场宇宙大清洗
the world gets a cosmic cleansing.
在恐龙之前
Before the dinosaurs,
生活着一些像马蹄蟹一样的生物
there were these horseshoe crab-looking thingies.
好恶心
Ugh! Yuck.
突然有一天 这座山脉的底部
Then, at the bottom of this mountain range,
被行星击中
an asteroid hit.
嘣！再见
Boom! Bye-bye.
然后 恐龙 山脉 行星
Next, dinosaurs, mountain range, asteroid.
嘣！再见
Boom! Bye-bye.
接下来会发生的事 哺乳动物们
And coming up next, mammals.
山脉 行星 嘣！
Mountain range, asteroid, boom!
再见
Bye-bye.
愚蠢的哺乳动物
Stupid mammals.
我们就是哺乳动物
That's us.
没错 她来了
Yep, and there she is.
行星之母正嘶吼着朝我们冲来
The mother of all asteroids screaming towards us.
这次即使躲到地下去也没用
Even going underground won't save us this time.
之前没有这东西的
Hey, that wasn't there before.
看看天上都变什么样了
And look what it's doing to the sky.
别担心 因为我有一个主意了
No worries. Because I've got a plan.
真的吗？去阻止一颗行星？
Really? To stop an asteroid?
听着 上两颗行星
Look, the last two asteroids.
都是在地球上的同一地点爆炸
have pummeled the earth in the same spot.
这次也会一样
And it's about to happen again.
我们得到那儿去
We've got to go there.
看看到底是什么在吸引行星
and see what's attracting the asteroid.
一旦我们知道为什么它会来…
Once we know why it's coming…
我们就能找到办法把它送到别处去
we can figure out how to send it somewhere else.
这个计划太蠢了
That plan is so dumb,
要是它长张脸 我非把它打得找不着北
I wish it had a face so I could smack it.
让我来整理下
Let me get this straight.
我们不但不要离这颗致命行星越远越好
Instead of running away from a deadly asteroid…
反之 你还要我们径直前往危险中心？
you want us to run directly towards it?
我知道这主意听起来不理想 可好消是…
I know it sounds suboptimal, but the good news is…
不管我们去哪儿都是死路一条
it'll kill us no matter where we went.
这我就放心了
Well, that's reassuring.
好 可是就算我们到达了撞击地点
Okay, but even if we get to the crash site…
我们又要怎么去改变
How are we supposed to change.
已经刻在石碑上的预言呢？
what is literally written in stone?
悲观的朋友
Ah, my cynical friend.
虽说恐龙被行星从地表抹去了
The dinos were wiped off the face of the Earth,
可是还是有些死里逃生了
but some escaped.
它们改变了自己的命运 我们也能
They changed their fate and we can change ours, too.
谁要和我一起去？
Who's with me?
你们怎么想？
So, what do you think?
事实上 我觉得黄鼠狼是对的
Honestly, I'm worried the weasel's right.
不！不能相信黄鼠狼
No! Don't listen to the weasel.
他就是个神志不清的疯子！
He's a raving loon!
抱歉 我比较喜欢扮演内心小恶魔
Sorry. I just love playing devil's advocate.
还喜欢打扮得美美的！
And looking fabulous!
巴克曾救过我们的命
Well, Buck has saved our lives before, right?
可如果这次他救不了我们呢？
But what if he can't this time?
我不知道该相信什么
I don't know what to believe.
我害怕我们的生命
But I'm afraid our lives will be over.
未曾绽放就要枯萎了
before they begin.
好了
Okay.
我们加入
I guess we're in.
喀什和艾迪奉命前来报道
Crash and Eddie reporting for duty.
粪命
Doody.
太棒了！脏话说的不错
Excellent! And dirty word processed.
现在 我们最好上路
Now, we better get on the road.
因为时间紧迫…
because time till impact is roughly…
只剩下2天4小时1分钟16秒
2 days, 4 hours, 1 minute and 16 seconds.
15秒 14秒…
15 seconds, 14 seconds…
我们明白了
I think we get it.
我想我们大家都明白了
I think we're all gonna get it.
我们看起来太帅了
Whoo! We look so cool.
这是什么东西？
Ugh. What is this stuff?
他在哪儿？一旦让我逮到那只独眼黄鼠狼…
Where is he? When I am through with that one-eyed weasel…
他就要变成无眼黄鼠狼了
He's going to need two eye patches.
我欣赏你的残暴 格蒂
I admire your bloodthirstitude, Gertie.
可是你听到他们的对话了
But you heard them.
行星就要来了
An asteroid is coming.
一切就要因此而改变了
This changes things.
我的天啊！这里真是冷死了
Holy snowballs! It's freezing up here.
我都缩成一团了
Parts are retracting into other parts.
你能别再像只小鹦鹉一样吗？
Would you please stop acting like a parakeet?
还好你遗传了你妈妈的眼睛…
It's a good thing you got your mother's eyes…
不然你真是一无是处
or you'd be totally useless.
这话太伤人了
Well, that's just hurtful.
你看见什么了？
What do you see?
一无所获 一无所获
Nothing. Nothing.
致命的行星朝我们奔腾而来
Deadly asteroid screaming towards Earth.
等下！看见他了
Wait! There he is.
糟了 他离我们好远
That's too bad. He is really far away.
就算飞行也赶不上他了
Probably too far to reach by flight.
算了 我们还是回家吧
Oh, well. Let's just go home.
我们不能撤退！
We are not retreating!
在那只黄鼠狼来到之前…
Until that weasel came along…
我们一家人一直本本分分的
our family made an honest living.
偷着蛋过日子
stealing dino eggs.
诚实的谋生手段 偷窃
An honest living. Stealing.
有点讽刺 你不觉得么？
Kind of ironic, don't you think?
还有 为什么要干掉那只黄鼠狼
Besides, why take out the weasel.
反正小行星迟早要把我们都干掉？
if the asteroid is just gonna take us out?
虽然你看的远 但是你的目光很短浅
So much sight. So little vision.
如果我们阻止了那只黄鼠狼和他的朋友们
If we stop the weasel and his friends.
不让他们改变小行星的路线
from diverting the asteroid…
嘭！
Kablooie!
它会杀死那只黄鼠狼和所有的其他人…
It kills the weasel and everyone else…
而我们可以飞上天空高枕无忧
while we glide safely above it all.
那会是我们的天堂
It'll be our paradise.
听起来不太现实
That's seems highly implausible.
从科学的角度说
Just from a scientific standpoint.
好吧 真是个好主意 哈！
Fine. It's a great plan. Dynamite!
简直是我听过的三四个
One of the top three or four.
物种灭绝计划中最棒的一个
species annihilation plans I've ever heard.
这么听起来就好多了
That's better.
现在让我们确保小行星撞上地球
Now let's make sure that asteroid hits.
为什么我们不能像正常的家庭一样
Why can't we just fear the apocalypse.
畏惧世界末日？
like a normal family?
哇哦！
Whoa!
嗯
Mmm.
嗯？
Mmm?
你在干什么 巴克？
What are you doing, Buck?
每块岩石都蕴含着一个故事
All rocks tell a tale.
我们从哪里来还有我们要到哪里去
Where we've been and where we're heading.
啊！
Ah!
然而 那个 是一坨屎
That, however, is a turd.
朱利安…
Julian…
我希望你知道如果我们没能成功…
I want you to know that if we don't make it…
如果我们永远不能结婚…
if we never get married…
你是我的唯一
you were the only one for me.
嗨 振作起来！
Hey, come on!
我们当然会成功 而且我们会结婚
Of course we'll make it, and we will get married.
但是也许宇宙在告诉我们 不会结婚
But maybe it's the universe telling us we won't.
哇哦！哇哦！哇哦！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
你们会让一个小小的…
You're going to let one tiny little…
300英里宽的迷你小行星搞砸你们的计划？
300-mile-wide asteroid ruin your plans?
假如明天都没有了
How can we think about our future.
我们怎么能计划未来？
when we may not have one?
嘿 我们会阻止这一切
Hey, we're going to stop this thing.
你们会结婚的
and you'll get married.
哒哒哒 吧嗒崩！
Bada-bing, bada-boom!
哦 不会爆炸 忘记我说的那个崩
Well, not boom. Forget I said boom.
我知道了！我来做你们的婚礼策划人！
I know! I'll be your wedding planner!
让你们注意力从
It'll take your mind.
世界末日转移到别处去
off all this end-of-the-world stuff.
事实上 我们刚刚打算跳过这个环节！
Actually, we were just gonna wing it!
低调一点
Keep it low-key.
什么？
What?
桃子 桃子 亲爱的
Peaches, Peaches. Sweetheart,
你不能这么跳过你人生中最开心的一天！
you don't just wing the happiest day of your life!
不可以 你应该抓紧并且珍视它
No, you seize it and you cherish it.
你带着美好的目标抓紧它
You strangle it with good intentions.
哦 让我们从你的发型开始
Ooh. Let's start with your hair.
往上梳扎个丸子头？很传统
Updo with a top bun? Traditional.
还是往下梳然后扎一个鱼尾辫 很俏皮
Or updo with a fishtail braid. Flirtatious.
但是有点俗套
But maybe a little trashy.
恶心
Ugh.
还有！吊袜带！
And garter belts!
艾迪是蕾丝雏菊版模特
Today, Ed is modelling laced daisies.
而喀什展现的是更优雅的常春藤…
While Crash is rocking a more elegant ivy…
不过小腿要够美
that's all about the calves.
哦 我们需要一张座位表！
Ooh. We need a seating chart!
单身的坐一桌 孩子们坐一桌
The singles table, the kids table,
奇怪的亲戚们坐一桌…
the weird relatives table…
体味重的坐一桌 再加两桌体味重的
the smelly table, two more smelly tables.
看看他
Look at him.
哦 你们一定会喜欢的
Oh, you're gonna love it.
谁像他那么走路？
Who walks like that?
哦！看看我
Oh! Look at me.
我是朱利安
I'm Julian.
别管小行星了
Forget the asteroid.
快拥抱我一下 岳父！
Gimme a hug, Bro-Dad!
看 有只漂亮小鸟
Look at that pretty bird there.
是啊！确实挺漂亮 眼光不错 曼尼
Yeah! That is a pretty bird. Good eye, Manny.
是的
Yeah.
天都要塌下来了…
The sky is literally falling…
她却觉得我们只需要跟着
and she thinks we're just gonna.
这个没计划 走路轻佻的家伙…
let her stroll into the wilderness…
一起走进茫茫荒地
with Mr. No Plans Bouncy Walk.
别挑他的错了
Stop picking on him.
别这样 艾丽 你不是还在生我的气吧？
Come on, El, you're not still mad at me, are you?
是的 我不生气了
No. I'm not still mad.
因为我不想这么度过
Because that's not how I want to spend.
没准是生命最后几天的日子
what could be our final days together.
但如果我们活下来了
But if we somehow survive.
躲过了那个毁灭我们星球的小行星…
that planet-killing hunk of space rock…
我还是会找你算账的
you're in for it.
如果我们活下来了 我们会失去我们的女儿
If we survive, we lose our daughter.
嗯 我也在想这个问题
Well, I've been thinking about that, too.
如果…
What if…
哦 我知道了！我们让他们分手 对么？
Ooh. I know! We destroy the relationship, right?
那样我们永远都不会让她走…
That way we never have to let her go…
她会永远做我们的小女儿！
and she'll just stay our little girl forever!
不 你这个精神病！
No, you psychopath!
不如我们劝他们住得离我们近一点？
What if we convince them to stay near us?
哦！这样更好
Oh! That's better.
我很喜欢 但是怎么办到呢？
I like it. But how?
用让她照我们意愿做事的老办法
The way we always get her to do what we want.
让她觉得这是她自己的主意
We make her think it's her idea.
你这个狡猾的家伙！
You sneaky, sneaky minx!
但愿这招还管用吧
Let's just hope we haven't lost our touch.
找到了！
Found it!
看 哺乳动物们！
Behold, mammals!
小行星的一部分已经偷偷溜进来了
A sneak preview of the asteroid to come.
来自太空的石头 从宇宙新鲜出炉
A space rock. Fresh from the cosmos.
嗯 嗯 嗯
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
我尝到了铁 碳
I taste iron, carbon.
哦！还有一点点镍
Oh! And a hint of nickel.
宇宙尝起来很孤独
Space tastes lonely.
嘿 看！我又找到了一块
Hey, look! I found another one.
我也是！
Me, too!
嘿！你的把我的吸住了
Hey! Yours is attracted to me.
不 你的把我的吸住了
No. Yours is attracted to me.
我们太有吸引力了！
We're just too attractive!
力量惊人！最后活命的几个小时
Stupendous! Now we have something.
我们有东西玩了
to play with during our final hours.
你没领会到重点 老虎
You're missing the point, Tiger.
他们是有磁性的
They're magnets.
如果这些来自太空的石头都有磁性…
And if these space rocks are magnetic…
那个也是
so is that.
这只能证明一个问题
This can only mean one thing.
也就是说…
And that would be…
不要介意
Allow me.
哇哦！
Whoa!
我们在哪？
Where are we?
你们在我的头脑里
You are in my brain.
有点冷啊
Hmm. Kind of chilly.
绅士们 这是我们现在知道的
Gentlemen, here's what we know.
来自太空的岩石？有磁性的 小行星？也是有磁性的
Space rocks? Magnetic. Asteroid? Also, magnetic.
著名的天体物理学家 尼尔·德巴克·黄鼠狼！
Famed astrophysicist Neil deBuck Weasel!
他很了解宇宙
He knows the cosmos.
根据事实 还有人体工学…
Ipso facto, thusly and ergo…
撞击点一定还有很多这样的东西
the crash site must have a heap of these things.
吸引着小行星
attracting the asteroid.
毕达哥拉斯巴克 他找到了正确的切入点
Ooh. Pythagoras Buck. He's got the right angle.
如果我们利用这个磁力
What if we use the magnets.
来把小行星吸引到别处呢？
to attract the asteroids somewhere else?
比如 朝非地球方向
As in, not towards Earth.
理论上讲
Theoretically speaking,
如果我们能把足够的磁石射向宇宙…
if we can launch enough of these into space…
他们会使小行星偏离轨迹
they will pull the asteroid off course.
因此 拯救世界
Thus, saving the world.
所以 我们需要去撞击点…
So, we just need to go to the crash site…
把大量的的磁石射到太空中
and launch a bunch of rocks into space.
很简单 是不是？
That's easy, right?
是啊是啊 听起来真是小菜一碟呢
Oh, yeah. Sounds like a real piece of cake.
这就是进展！
This is progress!
现在我们明确知道该怎么办了
Now we know exactly what we don't know how to do.
出发吧 哺乳动物们！
Vamanos, mammals!
沿着这条路一直走我们就会到达撞击点
This trail will take us directly to the crash site.
好的 孩子们
All right, kids.
让我们做点有趣的事
Let's have some fun.
好的 各位 沿着这条路走
Okay, everyone. Follow the trail.
不要离开这条路
Never leave the trail.
嗯？
Hmm?
呃 大家离开这条路
Okay, everyone. Leave the trail.
进树林 快点 快点
Into the forest. Chop, chop.
但你刚才说…
But you just said…
你知道我很神经的 快跟上
You know I'm crazy. Come on.
我喜欢树荫 你们不喜欢么？
I love the shade. Don't you?
招数不错 黄鼠狼
Well played, weasel.
盯紧点 孩子们
Stay sharp, kids.
他们不可能永远藏着
They can't hide forever.
嘿 巴克
Hey, Buck.
你有什么渡河的建议么？
You have a suggestion for getting around the river?
让我们看看这远古智慧石碑如何引导我们
Let's see if the tablet's ancient wisdom will guide us.
让我的哺乳动物们通过！
Let my mammals pass!
这怎么可能起作用
That's never gonna work.
祖先已给了我们安全的通道
The ancients grant us safe passage.
太好了！
Sweet!
哇 这里的空气有点奇怪
Wow, the air feels strange.
呃…
Uh…
迪亚哥？
Diego?
怎么了？
What?
我们终于有超能力了！
Finally! We have superpowers!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们正在穿越一场电磁爆
we have wandered into an electrical storm.
我建议离树远一点
I suggest we all stay away from the trees.
好的 没问题
Sure, no problem.
我们又没走在树林里
It's not like we're in a forest.
孩子 大自然母亲显然心情很不好
Boy, Mother Nature sure is in a bad mood lately.
好的一面是我们都可以在这里相互扶持
Good thing we're all here to help each other.
像我经常说的 团结在一起才能活命
Oh, like I always say, stay close, stay alive.
他们在那！
There they are!
没什么遮挡
Right out in the open.
你们能再蠢一点么？
How stupid can you be?
来吧 孩子们 俯冲！
Come on, kids. Dive!
大家尽量不要产生任何的摩擦
Everyone, try not to create any sort of friction.
不要摩擦 明白
No friction. Got it.
好的 棒棒的
Yup. Cool beans.
摩擦是这样么？
Friction is what now?
哦 不
Oh, no.
快点！我们离开这
Come on! Let's get out of here.
快点 奶奶
Hurry, Granny.
别催我
Don't you hurry me.
我被雷劈的次数…
I've been struck by lightning more times…
啊！奶奶！
Ahh! Granny!
…比你吃的盐还多
…than you've had hot breakfasts.
桃子！
Peaches!
朱利安 别动！
Julian, don't move!
我有办法了
I have an idea.
我来了 亲爱的！
I'm coming, sweetheart!
朱利安 你为什么不帮她？
Julian, why aren't you helping her?
等下！不 曼尼 她…
Wait! No, Manny, she…
呃 你们在干什么？
Uh, what are you guys doing?
帮忙？
Helping?
那 「不帮忙」 会怎样？
What would "not helping" look like?
嘿 爆炸头！
Hey, zapheads!
哇哦！
Whoo!
曼尼 准备跑
Manny, get ready to run.
快点 我们走！
Come on, let's go!
大家都跑出来了吗？
Everybody make it?
希拉 曼尼 喀什 艾迪 艾丽 奶奶
Shira, Manny, Crash, Eddie, Ellie, Granny.
该死！我的手指不够数了
Aw, shoot! I'm out of fingers.
巴克 巴克在哪？
Buck. Where's Buck?
你们听到了吗？
Do you hear that?
一个孩子！
A baby!
那里面有个孩子！
There's a baby in there!
巴克 等一下！太危险了
Buck, wait! It's too dangerous.
他死了
He's gone.
我简直不能相信
I can't believe it.
没有你我们怎么撑下去 巴克
Don't know how we'll go on without you, Buck.
好吧 我们走
All right, let's go.
是巴克！
It's Buck!
我在这 别担心 我在这
I got you. Don't worry, I got you.
不怕了 不怕了
There you are. There.
大家打个招呼吧
Say "hi, " everyone.
啊？
Huh?
她是不是超可爱？
Isn't she gorgeous?
他怎么知道是女孩？
How can he tell it's a she?
哦
Oh.
多可爱的小宝贝
Such a good little poochie-woochie.
我就是确定一下 这是个南瓜 是么？
Just to be clear, that's a pumpkin, right?
她有点黄疸 但是我觉得她会没事的
She has a little jaundice, but I think she'll be okay.
你会没事的
Yes, you will.
我觉得我该叫你… 布朗温
I think I'll call you… Bronwyn.
嗯 小老弟？我们需要你回到眼前的地球上来
Um, little buddy? We need you back on planet Earth.
小行星还在那呢 好么？
While it's still here. Okay?
你说的对 哺乳动物
Right you are, mammal.
谁要从凶猛的小行星手里拯救地球呀？
Who wants to save the world from the fiery asteroid?
是你！
You do!
好了 哺乳动物们 我们今晚就在这休息吧
Okay, mammals. Let's stop here for the night.
休息？那世界末日
Stop? What about the whole.
这件事怎么办呢？
end of the world collision thing?
哦 小行星还有一天才来
Oh, asteroid's still a day off.
而且正如我祖父曾说过的…
And like my grandfather used to say…
「早霞不出门 晚霞行千里」
"Red sky at night, sailor's delight."
晚上出紫霞 谁动了我的搓脚油？
Purple sky at night, who moved my foot cream?
「我需要我的搓脚油啊」
"I need my foot cream."
我爷爷是个糊涂易怒的黄鼠狼
Grampy was a confused and angry weasel.
你太搞笑了 朱利安
You are so funny, J.
行了！你才逗
Stop! You're funny.
放轻松 我的老虎兄弟
Take it easy, my brother from a tiger mother.
明儿见了 朱老弟
Hasta manana, J-man.
那是什么？
What was that?
什么那是什么？
What was what?
哦 那个啊！是一个很酷的道别方式
Oh, that! It's a cool way to peace out.
朱利安教我的
Julian taught it to me.
哦 我很高兴世界末日联络了你俩的感情
Well, I'm glad the apocalypse is bringing you together.
他是一个好孩子 曼尼 我喜欢他的人生观
He's a good kid, Manny. I like his philosophy.
给他一个机会 多和他接触一下
Give him a chance. Bond with him.
∮ 拆穿它们 点燃它们 毁灭他们 ∮
∮ So light 'em up, up, up ∮
∮ Light 'em up, up, up ∮
∮ 拆穿它们 点燃它们 毁灭他们 以我的火之力 ∮
∮ Light 'em up, up, up I'm on fire ∮
接触！是个不错的想法！
Bonding! That's a good idea!
对啊 明白了
Oh, right. Got you.
你去搞定朱利安 我有办法对付桃子
You take Julian. I got an idea for Peaches.
嘿 小伙计
Hey, Bro-Kid.
嘿 老伙计 你是来一起摇滚的吗？
Oh, hey, Bro-Dad. You here to rock out?
行了 并没这个打算…
Okay. Instead of that…
但是睡前来发游戏怎么样？
how about a game before bedtime?
真的假的！你想和我玩游戏？哇！
No way! You want to play a game with me? Wow!
一千倍的荣幸是多荣幸？
What is honored times 1, 000?
不！一百万倍荣幸是多少？
No! Times one million?
因为不管是多少荣幸 我就那么荣幸
'Cause whatever that equals, is how honored I am.
所以 就是 「同意」 了？
So, is that a "yes"?
当然 必须是 「同意」 简直不能更 「同意」 ！
Yes, that's a "yes". It's the most "yes"!
而且是 「同意」 后面拖很长的音那种…
It's like "yes" with a bunch of s's…
同意意意意意意意
so it's like "yessssssssssssssssssss."
好极了！
Great!
我在冰上等你！
I'll see you on the ice!
开心了吗？
Happy?
喔！
Whoa!
哦 天啊
Oh, boy.
你觉得自己准备好可以独当一面了吗？
So, do you think you're ready to go out roaming on your own?
不是我一个人 我还有朱利安
I won't be alone. I'll have Julian.
当然 但是满天飞的都是小行星…
Sure. But with asteroids flying…
无家可归
no home to speak of.
而且无人帮助…
and absolutely no support system…
你确定能应对…
do you think you'll be ready for…
这个了吗？
this?
我是一个小北鼻
I'm a wittle baby.
想象一下 你在森林当中 寻找食物…
Imagine. You're in the woods, looking for food…
你的孩子生病了 你该怎么办？
and your baby gets sick. What do you do?
呃…
Uh…
错！摇晃会让她感觉更糟糕！
No! Jiggling makes her feel worse!
哦 不！现在你大一点的孩子
Oh, no! Now your older toddler.
摔伤了膝盖还塞住了鼻子
has a skinned knee and a stuffy nose.
妈咪 抱抱我！
Mommy, hold me!
现在你的孩子们都在哭
Now your babies are crying.
你又没有食物而且
You have no food and then.
又来了一个狂犬病兽跟你对峙！
you come face to face with a rabid beast!
我是一个狂犬病兽 我会给孩子传染狂犬病
I am a rabid beast who gives rabies to babies.
还有一个纵火犯在逍遥法外
And there's an arsonist on the loose.
没有我们的帮助你要如何独自解决这一切？
How are you going to handle all this without our help?
桃子 收工！
Peaches, out!
那只是一些简单容易的事情
That's just the easy stuff.
还有更多需要我们保护的
There's a lot more we still need to cover.
呃… 北鼻拉粑粑了
Uh… Baby made a poopie.
我是精湛演技派的 所以请给我换尿布
I'm a method actor, so I will need to be changed.
哦！就差一点！
Oh! So close!
这些冰球跑的好快
These pucks go fast.
只需要一直盯紧冰球 直到用球棒接住它
Just watch the puck all the way into the stick.
哦！我做到了！
Oh! I did it!
真遗憾你和桃子要搬走了
Too bad you and Peaches are moving away.
如果你们留下来 我们可以一直这样玩
If you stayed, we could do this all the time.
好吧 给我来点高难度的！
Okay. Show me the heat!
我是冰球忍者！
I'm like a hockey ninja!
嘿 桃子！
Hey, Peaches!
貌似你有一个新的冰球玩伴
Looks like you got a new hockey partner.
可以取代你爸爸啦
to replace your dad.
糟了
Oh, no.
朱利安！
Julian!
还真是想不通 他为什么想要搬远一点
Such a mystery why he wants to move far away.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to do it.
那孩子没有反应能力也不能怪我啊
It's not my fault the kid has no reflexes.
你怎么能这样对他！
How could you do that to him?
我以为你喜欢朱利安
I thought you liked Julian.
我确实喜欢朱利安
I do like Julian.
你表现的可不像啊
Well, you don't act like it.
你把他当块拦路石一样看待他
When you look at him, all you see is an obstacle.
也许更糟 把他当靶子
Or worse, a target.
而在我看来 他是一个温暖的…
But I see a sweet guy…
尽一切努力想得到你认可的人
who's trying his hardest to impress you.
- 桃子 - 好了！你们俩 该停下了！
- Peaches. - No! Both of you, just stop!
如果我们活下来了 我还是会结婚
If we survive, I'm still getting married.
我还是会离开家
and I'm still leaving home.
不管你们开心与否
Whether you're happy for me or not.
别给我那种眼神 她说了 你俩
Don't give me that look. She said both.
也就是说你也有份
That means you, too.
然后这个小小的行星
And this widdle astewoid.
就滴溜溜的 一路回家了
went wee, wee, wee, all the way home.
嘿…
Hey…
因为粑粑和他的朋友们拯救了世界
Because Daddy and his fwiends saved the world.
∮ 要不是那个翼龙会飞 ∮
∮ And if that pterodactyl don't fly ∮
∮ 粑粑就会戳瞎他剩下的那只眼睛 ∮
∮ Daddy's gonna blind his remaining eye ∮
好梦 小家伙
Sweet dreams, little one.
好幸运的南瓜！
Lucky pumpkin!
有一个有爱的爸爸一定很棒
It must be nice to have a loving father.
好了 开始吧 你能做到的 罗杰
Okay, here we go. You can do this, Roger.
耶！绑架喽！
Yay! Kidnapping!
很抱歉 但这不是我的主意
Look I'm sorry. It's not me.
我永远不会做这种事情
I would never do something like this.
是我爸爸让做的 他很疯狂
It's my father. He's crazy.
我简直不相信他做到了！
I can't believe he pulled it off!
干得漂亮 笨蛋！
Way to go, dum-dum!
哦 谢谢 老爸
Oh. Thanks, Dad.
那又怎样！我也能做到
Whatever! I could've done the same thing.
看看 看看
Well, well.
看来你还没阻止那个小行星啊
Looks like you're not stopping that asteroid now,
是吗 黄鼠狼？
are you, weasel?
哈？
Huh?
那不是黄鼠狼 那是…
That's not the Weasel. That's…
- 我也不知道那是什么 - 嗯
- I don't know what that is. - Hmm.
喔！
Whoa!
我的大限到了吗 天使？
Is it my time, angel?
大限什么？
Time for what?
我正走向光明
I'm coming to the light.
等不及要见见那些已经死去的烦人亲戚了
Can't wait to see all those dead relatives I hate.
啊！快下来！快下来！快下来！
Ahh! Get it off! Get it off! Get it off!
去帮帮你姐姐
Go help your sister.
但是 爸爸…
But, Dad…
啊！是恶魔天使！
Ahh! Demon angel!
敢打扰你奶奶 屁股就要开花
Mess with Granny, get knocked on your fanny.
这样不就完事了么 嗯
And that's how it's done. Hmm.
有人吗？天使？
Hello? Angel?
我在天堂吗？
Am I in heaven?
这里好暗好黏糊啊
It's so dark and squishy in here.
哈？
Huh?
哦 不！我还是可以看见亮光
Oh, no! I can still see the light.
老爸！我来救你
Pop! I'll save you.
你好！
Hello!
呃 也许这样对大家都好
Oh, well. Probably for the best.
- 是啊 也许是 - 绝对是
- Yeah, probably. - Definitely.
哎呀！
Crikey!
嗯
Mmm.
天啊 巴克 你都干了些什么？
Good gravy, Buck. What have you done?
好了 哺乳动物们 该出发了
All right, mammals. Time to get moving.
我们先不要纠结这个问题 但是没错…
Now let's not linger on this, but, yes…
我把石碑看错了 那颗小行星离我们近了许多
I read the tablet wrong. The asteroid is a lot closer.
糟了
Uh-oh.
等一等 奶奶在哪？
Wait a second. Where's Granny?
奶奶？奶奶？
Oh. Granny? Oh, Granny?
可能是她走丢了？
Maybe she wandered off?
说不定她也被冰球砸到脑袋了？
Maybe she got hit in the head with a puck?
是的！也可能是只三凶狠庞大的
Yes! And maybe she was abducted.
恐龙鸟为了报复我…
by homicidal 30-foot dino-birds…
把她掳走了
seeking revenge on me.
都是不错的假设 我支持被冰球砸了
All good theories. I'm going to go with the puck.
我就知道！
I knew it!
所以一直有群巨型恐龙鸟追捕我们？
So this whole time we've been chased by giant dino-birds?
才三个而已！我不想打击士气
Oh, only three! I didn't want to damage morale.
可不是 知道这消息之前
Right. Because before this,
我们一直都是无忧无虑地前进着
we were on a carefree pleasure cruise.
等等
Wait a second.
我闻到她的气味了 快来！
I've got her scent. Come on!
哇！
Whoa!
哺乳动物们 我们到了！
Mammals, we've made it!
这就是撞击点
The crash site.
这肯定就是之前那颗小行星留下的残余部分
This must be what's left of the previous asteroid.
呃 巴克？你的太空石！
Uh, Buck? Your space rocks!
以那么大的引力
We could definitely divert the asteroid.
我们绝对能转移小行星的轨迹！
with a magnet that size!
那块石头简直是庞然大物
I mean that thing is enormous.
简直无敌大 简直…
It's massive, it's…
没有任何可能搬得动
going to be impossible to get off the ground.
绝对有可能
It's entirely possible.
只是还不知道办法
In a way that we don't know about yet.
那恐龙鸟怎么办？
But what about the dino-birds?
奶奶又怎么办？
And what about Granny?
闻不到了
Nothing.
真遗憾 希德
I'm sorry, Sid.
奶奶 我温暖 毒舌的奶奶
Oh, Granny. My sweet, malicious Granny.
为什么总是老人先走？
Why does it always have to be the old ones who go first?
为什么？
Why?
我依然能听见她甜美 刺耳的声音…
I can still hear her sweet, shrill voice…
在天国尖叫着
shrieking from the afterlife.
奶奶还活着！
Granny's alive!
她遇到麻烦了！
And she's in trouble!
奶奶？
Granny?
- 奶奶？- 奶奶？
- Granny? - Granny?
她还好吧？
Is she okay?
呃 我也不确定
Uh, I'm not sure.
放开我的奶奶！
Unhand my Granny!
停手我就不给你小费
You do and you don't get a tip.
让这只美丽的树懒开心
Making this beautiful sloth happy.
就是我最大的回报
is all the payment I need.
你看？人家浪兔子多懂事
You see? Hunky bunny gets it.
奶奶！
Granny!
小行星里还住着只兔子？
There's a bunny living in the asteroid?
我可没预料到这茬
Did not see that coming.
那你应该来看看这个！
Wait till you see this!
耶！
Yeah!
弧形滑道高速旋转！
Catching mad air on the half-pipe!
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
你觉得他们知不知道
Do you think they know.
自己住在一个磁力源里？
they are living in a magnetic bull's-eye?
看不出来这里为世界末日来临
Doesn't look like a lot of.
做过多少准备
doomsday prepping going on in here.
我简直不能相信！
I can't believe it!
有客人！
Visitors!
我们从来没有过客人
We've never had visitors.
谁能掐我一下 或者我能掐你一下吗？
Somebody pinch me. Or should I pinch you?
等等 我还是两个都掐一下
Wait, I'll pinch both of us.
我脑袋被撞了吗？这里到底发生了什么？
Did I hit my head? What's happening here?
我真的希望这不是一个… 哦！
I sure hope this isn't a… Oh!
梦！
dream!
∮ 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Dream Weaver ∮
∮ 我相信你能带我穿过黑暗 ∮
∮ I believe you can get me through the night ∮
这家伙？说真的？
This guy? For real?
随便啦
Whatever.
你好 帅哥
Hello, handsome.
我是布鲁克
I'm Brooke.
多么精致的骨架结构
Ooh. Such exquisite bone structure.
多么强有力的下巴
Such a strong jaw.
我都仙仙欲醉了！
I'm getting butterflies!
我都快恶心吐了
I'm getting nauseous.
很抱歉打断你们怪异的爱情纽带…
Sorry to interrupt this weirdo love connection…
但是我们真的有急事
but we're kind of in a hurry.
如果我们不尽快采取办法的话…
If we don't do something fast…
那个小行星会把我们全部炸成碎片
that asteroid is gonna blow us all to smithereens.
哦 听起来很急迫
Oh. That sounds urgent.
我最好带你们去见他
I better take you to him.
谁是 「他」 ？你们的头儿？
Who's "him"? Your leader?
他是我们的一切
He is our everything.
他洞察一切
He sees all.
他知晓一切
He knows all.
而且很好闻！
And smells amazing!
好吧 他听起来很棒 我们走吧！
Okay. He sounds great. Let's go!
好极了 这边请
Brilliant. Right this way.
喔吼！
Whoo-hoo!
爽！
Yes!
请不要将您的腿和胳膊
Please keep your arms and legs.
伸出飞行船外
inside the tram at all times.
但请让您的思绪随意飘荡…
But allow your spirit to roam free…
在岩托邦
in Geotopia.
我预感会很不错
I have a good feeling about this.
也许他能帮助我们
Maybe he'll be able to help us.
她确实说过他知晓一切
She did say he knows all.
而一切有好多好多！
And all's a lot!
他在这
Here he is.
冥想大师 究极宁静
The Master of Meditation, the Supreme Serene…
四届冥思世界冠军
the four-time Heavy Thoughts champion of the world!
那是羊驼吗？我讨厌羊驼
Is that a llama? I hate llamas.
他们爱吐口水还特别臭
They spit and smell.
她也是
So does she.
我们也是！
So do we!
欢迎光临 哺乳动物们！
Greetings, mammals!
香格里喇嘛现在…
The Shangri Llama will see you…
接见你们
now.
哦 太好了
Ooh. Wonderful.
所以他在哪？
So where is he?
他在这 跟你说话呢
He is here. Talking to you.
哦 我明白了 他是个口技艺人
Oh, I get it. He's a ventriloquist.
你就是个木偶
and you're the dummy.
- 不 你是蠢蛋 - 不 你是木偶
- No, you're the dummy. - No, you're the dummy.
不 你才是蠢蛋
No, you're the dummy.
这就是要拯救众生的人
This is the guy that's going to save us.
- 小心 - 你是蠢蛋
- Look within. - You're the dummy.
太恶心了！我喜欢！
Disgusting! Loved that!
新话题 我们都快要死了
New topic. We're all about to die.
这可不好 精神压力是个元凶
Well, that's no good. Stress is a killer.
让我们放松身体拥抱新知吧
Let us loosen our limbs and open our minds.
下犬式！
Downward Dog!
呃… 开玩笑呢？
Uh… Seriously?
我可以等 我有全世界的时间
I'll wait. I have all the time in the world.
其实 你并没有全世界的时间
Actually, you don't have all the time in the world.
我们都没有 你看到了吗 天上有这个玩意
None of us do. You see, there's this thing in the sky.
哦 那个要把眼睛闪瞎
Oh. That blinding light.
每分钟都要大一圈的亮光吗？
that seems to get larger by the minute?
它怎么了？没问题啊
What about it? Seems fine to me.
尊敬的柔韧国王啊
With all due respect, Your Twistiness,
那是个小行星
that's an asteroid.
它被磁力吸引到了这个地方
It's magnetically attracted to this place.
并直冲我们过来了
and it's heading straight for us.
是嘛！
Aha!
它一定很渴望我们的磁性水晶
It must desire our magnetic crystals.
这该怪谁？
Well, who can blame it?
它们确实不一般
They're really quite something.
你知道它们可以使你永葆年轻吗？
Did you know their power grants eternal youth?
我已经四百多岁了 没错
I am over 400 years old. Mmm-hmm.
- 这不可能 - 当然可能
- That's not possible. - Sure it is.
我326岁了 呜呼！
I'm 326! Whoo!
是吗？你看着最多275岁
Huh? You don't look a day over 275.
我们年轻 快乐 安全 无忧无虑
We are young, happy and safe. And we always will be.
感谢岩托邦！
Thanks to Geotopia!
太棒了 真不错
Kudos. It is lovely.
现在我们想个办法把它发射进太空吧
Now, let's figure out a way to launch it into space!
不好意思 你想摧毁我们的家园？
I'm sorry. You want to destroy our home?
不管怎样它都会被摧毁的
It'll be destroyed either way.
但是如果我们能把这个磁性物质
But if we propel this magnetic material.
发射进大气层…
into the atmosphere…
我们就可以改变小行星的轨迹并拯救所有人
we can change the asteroid's path and save everyone.
你怎么看？
What do you say?
毛毛虫式！
Caterpillar!
这是同意？还是…
So, is that a yes? Or…
你脊柱下方储存了
You are storing a lot of hostility.
太多的戾气
in your lower spine.
香格里喇嘛 我们怎么才能…
Shangri Llama, how are we gonna…
节奏小鸡 摇晃果冻 土豆泥
Funky Chicken. Jiggy Jelly. Mashed Potato.
你的柔韧性确实不错
Your flexibility is a sight to behold.
我们到底怎么
Now how the devil.
才能发射这些水晶？
are we going to launch these crystals?
你不能 这不可能
You can't. It's impossible.
呼！我太累了
Whoo! I am bushed.
很开心见到你们
Awesome meeting you guys.
随便逛逛吧 或者 随你们便吧
Feel free to hang or, you know, whatever.
就这样了 他是我们最后的希望
That's it. He was our last hope.
我们要完了
We're doomed.
没错 我们只上了节免费瑜伽课
Yeah. All we got was a free yoga class.
说到瑜伽课…
On that subject…
你们能搭把手吗？
could you help me, please?
我的鼻子和屁股要亲密接触了
My nose is dangerously close to my butt.
呃 希德 你为什么有两条尾巴？
Uh, Sid, why do you have two tails?
我也在呢
I'm in here, too.
嘿 不要哭
Hey, don't cry.
往好的方面想
Look on the bright side.
我们过去的人生将会在眼前闪回
We get to see our lives flash before our eyes.
我可以再经历一次…
That means I get to fall in love with you…
爱上你的感觉
all over again.
只有你才能把世界末日
Only you can make the end of the world.
说得像件好事一样
sound like a good thing.
我们把她培养的很好
We did a good job raising her.
她比我们知道的要更坚强
She's stronger than we know.
两天前 我愿付出一切把她留在我们身边
Two days ago, I'd have given anything to keep her with us.
现在我愿付出一切看到她结婚
Now I'd give anything just to see her get married,
并搬出去
and leave home.
和她的孩子们玩耍 和她丈夫跳舞
Play with her kids, dance with her husband.
当她丈夫忘记结婚纪念日时候冲他发脾气
Yell at him when he forgets their anniversary.
这很美好 不是吗？
It was a good one, wasn't it?
我们的生活 你 我 还有桃子
Our life. You, me, and Peaches.
这最好了
The best.
哦 布鲁克
Oh, Brooke.
你太漂亮了
You're so pretty.
你把我口齿不清的毛病都治好了
You take my lisp away.
我赌你对所有女孩说过这些话
I bet you say that to all the girls.
我试了 但她们通常都跑的太快了
I try. But usually they run away too fast.
哦 你真是太浪漫了
Oh, you're such a romantic.
嘿 我知道这么说太心急了…
Hey, I know this is going to sound super forward…
但是你想成为我的人生伴侣吗？
but will you be my mate for life?
布鲁克 我不知道该说什么了
Oh, Brooke, I don't know what to say.
这才12分钟而已
It's only been twelve minutes.
你怎么这么慢？
What took you so long?
太好了！这是我见过
Yes! This has been.
最棒的世界末日了
the best last day on Earth ever.
钻石！我需要一颗钻石
A diamond! I need a diamond!
我去哪才能找到…
Where can I find a…
完美
Oh! Perfect.
别别别 希德 亲爱的 别这么做
No, no, no. Sid, sweetie, don't do that.
胡说 要把最好的给我唯一…的…真爱
Nonsense. Only the best for my one… true… love.
糟了！
Whoopsies!
不 不 不！
No, no, no!
噢！傻瓜！智障！
Oaf! Simpleton! Nincompoop!
你在和她说话还是我？
You talking to her or me?
这堵墙是唯一让我们永葆年轻的东西
That wall was the one thing keeping us young.
现在我们都完了！完了！
Now we're all doomed! Doomed!
而且现在 我觉得我发烧了
And now, I think I have a fever.
太谢谢了 傻子！
Thank you so much, doofus!
嘿！别激动 喇嘛！
Hey! Easy there, Llama!
这傻瓜是我的梦中情人
This is the doofus of my dreams.
他是出于好意
He meant well.
哦 他出于好意
Oh, he meant well.
关我什么事啊？
Who cares?
说好的安静祥和去哪了
So much for serenity.
三百年的和谐融洽…
300 years of peace and harmony…
就被一个宇宙超级无敌
undone by one colossally, incredibly…
大傻瓜树懒毁了！
stupendously stupid sloth!
布鲁克
Oh, Brooke.
哇！你们都老成这样了
Wow! You guys got old.
咱们俩玩完了
Whatever we had, it's over.
这就是爱上一匹野马的后果
That's what happens when you date a cougar.
我非常抱歉 喇嘛先生
I'm really sorry, Mr. Llama.
抱歉 抱歉？
Sorry. Sorry?
抱歉可修不好这堵墙
Sorry doesn't fix the wall now,
是吧 你个小…
does it, you little…
我需要来个泡泡浴或者按摩
I need a bubble bath or a massage.
谁会针灸？
Who knows acupuncture?
我需要把我的怒气发泄出来 发泄出来！
I need to let my anger out. Let it out!
我被压抑的太久了
I've been pent up too long.
我想打人 有人能把脸伸过来吗？
I want to hit something. Someone give me their face.
就是那个！被压抑的能量
That's it! Pent-up energy.
地球上最强劲的推进设备
Earth's most powerful propulsion device.
就在我们眼前
is right in front of us.
谁？这个吐痰大仙吗？
Who? Spitty McGee here?
是火山！
The volcano!
这就是我们的磁铁发射器
That's our magnet launcher.
我们需要做的就是把它周围的蒸汽出口封死
All we need to do is seal the steam vents around it.
这个计划太疯狂了！
That's a crazy plan!
你才是疯狂计划
You're a crazy plan.
这根本行不通
That doesn't even make any sense.
那你又是什么？逻辑教授吗？
And what are you? A professor of logic?
萌萌绒猫教授
Professor Kitty McWhiskers.
就职于喵喵喵喵喵大学的…
of the University of Meow Meow Meow Meow…
你看到了吗？巨大的压力
You see? Tremendous pressure.
可以导致巨大的爆炸
leads to a tremendous explosion.
你还自称教授呢
And you call yourself a professor.
好 我们需要把所有的水晶
Right. We need all the crystals.
装到火山里去 赶快
loaded into the volcano, pronto.
什么？不行！
What? No!
我是不会把水晶给你的
I'm not giving you my crystals.
我需要它们来重建我们的庇护所
We need them to rebuild our sanctuary.
我能提醒一下大家岩托邦并不属于你们吗
May I remind you Geotopia is not yours to keep.
不 你不可以
No, you may not.
它是从天上来的
It came from the sky,
现在我们需要把它还回去
and now it's time to give it back.
才不是！
Is not!
就是 你个老傻瓜
Is too, you old coot.
改变不容易 但它也是生命的一部分
Change isn't easy, but it's part of life.
是时候让我们重新去拥抱它了
It's time for us to embrace it again.
不管你喜不喜欢
Whether you like it or not.
我不喜欢！
Not!
听着 喇嘛 我要发火 烧你屁股了！
Listen, Llama, I will go nuts and granola on your butt!
所以你要么加入进来…
So either get on board…
要么去一边把自己卷成个麻花
or go twist yourself into a pretzel.
别妨碍我们干活
and na-ma-stay out of our way.
大家来啊
Come on, everybody.
把你们所有能找到的水晶都拿上
Grab every crystal you can find.
必须的 我们走吧！
Totally, let's do it!
别忘了 搬的时候用腿发力
And remember, lift with your legs.
太晚了
Too late.
听好了 星球保护小队
Listen up, planetary defense team.
第一步 要产生压力
Step one, build pressure.
就要封死火山排气孔
inside the volcano by sealing the vents.
蒸汽就不能出来了
No steam can escape.
如果有泄露的地方…
If there's a leak…
压力就会减弱
the pressure is weak.
第二步 把最大的磁性水晶
Step two, get the biggest magnetic crystals.
放进火山里
into the volcano.
要把它们发射到高空中去
They've got to be launched sky high.
来改变小行星原来的轨道
to pull the asteroid off course.
- 喝！- 哈！
- Heave! - Ho!
哇 哇！这个要炸！
Rah rah! Sis boom bah!
和小行星说 「拜拜」
Tell that asteroid "Uh-uh."
∮ 小行星 ∮
∮ Asteroid ∮
∮ 标签是什么意思？∮
∮ What does hash tag mean? ∮
∮ 我也不知道但听着好酷 ∮
∮ I don't know but it sounds cool ∮
∮ 那必须 ∮
∮ Totally ∮
∮ 别说了真够无聊 ∮
∮ I'm starting to get sick of it ∮
就是这了 朋友们 扔进火山口里
This is it, friends. Down the hatch.
每一个水晶都能起作用
Every crystal counts.
大伙们 好消息！
Good news, everyone!
我们比计划提前了六分钟
We're six minutes ahead of schedule.
冥冥之力在帮助我们
Somebody up there likes us.
坏消息！冥冥之力不想帮我们了
Bad news! Somebody up there doesn't like us.
我们比计划慢了六分钟！
We're six minutes behind schedule!
加倍工作 我们需要那个大水晶
Double time, everyone. We need that big crystal.
我来帮你 岳父！
Oh. Hey, Bro-Dad!
有人来了！
We got company!
我去蛋糕拿出来招待客人
Ooh. I'll put out the sponge cake.
瞄准
Steady.
不好意思
Sorry about this.
我现在内心真的很矛盾
I'm really conflicted right now.
这还差不多 罗杰 现在了结了他吧
That's more like it, Roger. Now finish him.
等等！等等 你不懂
Wait! Wait, you don't understand.
看到那个了吗？
You see that?
如果那个小行星撞上来 我们都会死
If that asteroid hits, we all die.
如果它撞上来 我们都会死
If it hits, we all die.
这就是你出错的地方
That's where you're wrong.
你们哺乳动物奔走逃命的时候…
See, while you run for your mammal lives…
我们会在高高的天空中 巡视一切
we'll be high in the sky, cruising above it all.
这是我听过最愚蠢的事了！
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard!
我们会像那些小鸟一样安全
We'll be as safe as those little birdies.
碰巧了
Lucky shot.
太巧了？
Very lucky shot?
我就知道 我是对的 根本就没有什么天堂
I knew it. I was right. There's no paradise.
什么？这么早就灭绝 我还很年轻！
What? I'm too young to go extinct!
她明白了 求你了 我们时间不多了
She gets it! Now, please, we haven't got much time!
你还等什么？杀了他啊！
What are you waiting for? Kill him!
不 爸爸 我不会让你这么做的
No, Dad. I won't let you.
你知道我为什么爱着这个家吗？
Do you want to know what I love about our family?
因为我们都活着
That we're alive.
比你的自豪感更重要的东西
There are more important things.
还有许许多多
than your pride right now.
如果你关心我们…
If you care about us…
你就不应该杀他
you should not kill him.
你应该帮助他 爸爸
You should help him, Dad.
爸爸 我不喜欢这么说
Pop, I hate to say this,
但是我这个奇葩小弟弟可能是对的
but my freaky little brother may be right.
作为父亲 我愿意与宿敌合作…
As a father, I would work with my worst enemy…
以确保我的小宝宝有个更美好的未来
to ensure a brighter future for my little one.
援兵来啦！
Reinforcements have arrived!
好了 罗杰 带路吧
All right, Roger. Lead the way.
哇！被赞同原来是这种感觉
Oh! So that's what approval sounds like.
继续飞 恐龙
Keep it up, dinos.
用你们的侏罗纪超能力！
Use that Jurassic super strength!
哔 哔 哔
Beep, beep, beep.
小心 孩子们！
Watch out, kids!
黄鼠狼着陆了
The weasel has landed.
我去把它推进去 你去找桃子和艾丽
I'll push it in. Go with Peaches and Ellie!
不！
No!
我不会离开你的！我们一起推！
I'm not leaving you! We'll do this together!
妈妈 他们在哪里？
Mom, where are they?
艾丽 必须让大家都离开火山
Ellie, we've got to get everyone off the volcano.
大家伙 蛋糕吃完了 但还有香肠！
Folks, I'm outta cake, but I got salami!
加速！加速！
Faster, faster!
蛋糕吃完了 但还有香肠！
I'm outta cake, but I got salami!
- 奶奶 走了！- 喂！喂！慢点儿！
- Granny, come on! - Hey! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
这样没用
This isn't working.
弧形滑道高速旋转！
Mad air on the half-pipe!
曼尼 我有办法了！
Manny, I have a plan!
让水晶滚下去！
We have to let the crystal go!
你知道我们是要把水晶丢入火山吧？
You know we're trying to get it in the volcano, right?
曼尼 和桃子一起生活是我唯一想要的
Manny, the only thing I want is a life with Peaches.
还有向你证明我自己
And to prove myself to you.
好吧 两样东西 我要两样
So, okay, two things. I want two things.
你真的认为我会浪费唯一的机会？
Do you really think I'd waste the only chance I have left?
好了 我们开始吧！
Okay, let's do it!
听我口令 一…
On my count. One…
二…
Two…
三！
Three!
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
奏效了吗？
Did it work?
太棒了！我收回说过一切关于你的坏话！
Yes! I take back everything I ever said about you!
等等 什么？
Wait, what?
我们赶紧离开这里！
Now let's get out of here!
怎么回事？
What happened?
也许是暴风雨前的平静？
Maybe it's the quiet before the crazy?
艾迪！
Eddie!
我们成功了 成功了！
We did it. We did it!
滚蛋 太空石！
In your face, space rock!
没错 宝贝！
Yeah, baby!
喔呼！太棒了！
Whoo-hoo! Yeah! Oh!
不要吻嘴唇 臭老头！
Not on the lips, geezer!
滚吧 愚蠢的石头
Hit the road, you stupid rock.
我们刚刚终止了世界末日！
We just stopped the doomsday clock!
没错！哇！真好！
Yes! Yeah! Whoa! All right!
孩子 过来 欢迎加入我们家
Bring it in, Bro-Son. Welcome to the family.
还有你 小疯子！
And you, you coconut!
我再也不会怀疑你了
I'll never doubt you again.
看到没？爸爸总是对的
See? Daddy's always right.
你长大了也要记得
Remember that when you're older.
你真的不能跟我们一起去吗？
Are you sure you can't come with us?
希德 我也想啊
Oh, Sidney, I wish I could.
但是 我们都知道 这样做才是最好的
But we both know this is for the best.
你还有你的大好人生
You've got your whole life in front of you.
而且这里有奶奶陪我
Besides, I'll have Granny to keep me company.
你也要留下吗？
You're staying, too?
你在开玩笑吧？这个地方超棒的！
Are you kidding? This place is great!
今晚有大型才艺表演 明天有裸体宾果！
Tonight's the big talent show, and tomorrow, naked bingo!
你来吗 格拉迪斯？
You coming, Gladys?
我的上了年纪可等不起了！
I ain't getting any younger! Whoo!
什么？我听不见你说什么！
What? I can't hear you!
- 什么？我听不见你说什么！- 什么？
- What? I can't hear you! - What?
你永远是我唯一真爱
You'll always be my one true love.
给你
Here.
哇！
Wow!
等一等
Hold on.
跟你一模一样
It looks just like you.
我们以后就可以永远在一起了
Now we'll be with each other forever.
再见 帅哥！
So long, handsome!
再见 希德！
Bye, Sidney!
只需要补充点纤维质
What you need is more fiber.
他说的对
He's right.
香格里喇嘛活力重现！
Shangri Llama's back on top, baby!
格拉迪斯？
Gladys?
你好呀 小帅哥！
Well, hello Teddy Bear!
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
浴池突然热辣了很多
Hot tubbin' just got a whole lot hotter.
太神奇了！这简直就是
Amazing! It's like some kind of.
「永葆青春泉！」
"Fountain of Never Getting Old!"
我们以后再研讨如何命名吧
Well, we can workshop the name later.
新娘在哪里？为什么新娘还没来？
Where's the bride? Why don't I have the bride?
因为你在跟树枝说话
'Cause you're talking into a twig.
妈妈 我不方便说话 我在参加婚礼
Mom, I can't talk. I'm at a wedding.
你说你不能说话是什么意思？
What do you mean you can't talk?
你和谁在一起？
Who are you with?
嗯 请问
Um, excuse me.
你们真的拯救了世界不被小行星毁灭？
Is it true you helped save the world from an asteroid?
嗯…
Um…
这是一个非常可怕的故事
That's a very scary story.
你们敢听吗？
You think you can handle it?
当然
Yeah.
有多可怕？
How scary?
当时我们… 哦！哦！
Well, we were… Oh! Oh!
嗨！
Hi!
离午夜十二点还有五分钟…
It was five minutes to midnight…
我们要和火山
and we were up against volcanoes,
恐龙鸟 还有世界末日对决
dino-birds, and the end of the world.
对了！还有僵尸！不要忘了僵尸！
Oh, and the zombies! Don't forget the zombies!
我们会成为出色的父母的
You know, we'd be great parents.
于是我对着野人说
So I turn to Bigfoot, and I say,
「听着 大家伙…」
"Listen, big guy…"
我不知道 我不知道！我该怎么办？
I don't know. I don't know! What am I gonna do?
亲爱的 别紧张 这很正常的
Sweetie, listen to me. This is normal, okay?
每个人都会紧张
Everyone gets nervous.
这是怎么回事？怎么了？
What's going on? What happened?
只是…
It's just…
我没法去 我怎么迈得出脚步？
I can't go. How can I go?
我不想离开你们
I don't wanna leave you guys.
嘿 小毛球…
Hey, Fuzzball…
还记得我们第一次打冰球的场景吗？
remember the first time that we played hockey?
你非常害怕踩到冰上
You were so afraid to get on the ice.
因为冰太滑了？
because it was slippery?
还记得我抱着你开始滑冰的样子吗？
Remember how I held you up while you started to skate?
当我知道你准备好了 我就放手
And when I knew you were ready, I let you go.
哦 爸爸
Aw, Dad.
我知道你准备好了 现在你要放手
I know you're ready. Now you have to let go.
我一直知道你需要一个特别的人
I always knew it would take someone very special.
与你意气相投
to match your spirit.
现在你找到他了 就像我当初一样
And you found him. Just like I did.
这是属于你的时刻 亲爱的
It's your time, sweetie.
出去看看世界 追逐梦想
See the world, chase your dreams.
无论什么时候你决定回来…
And whenever you decide to come back…
我们都会在这里 好吗？
we'll be here, okay?
好的
Okay.
你愿意…
Do you…
我愿意
I do.
你愿意…
And do you…
非常愿意
Most def.
我现在宣布你们…
I now pronounce you…
希德！
Sid!
布鲁克！
Brooke!
不好意思！
Oops!
太神奇了！
This is amazing!
你又变年轻了 而且不知怎么的 我还是单身
You're young again. And somehow, I'm still single.
我猜老天对我们露出了笑容
I guess the universe was smiling on us.
我有很多问题要问你
I have so many questions for you.
发生了什么？你是怎么找到我的？
What happened? How'd you find me?
你有没有尝过那虾？
Have you tried the shrimp?
嘘 闭上你那可爱的小嘴
Shh. Close that pretty little mouth of yours.
认真听
and just listen.
这首歌献给我梦中树懒
This is dedicated to the sloth of my dreams.
那家伙？说真的？
That guy? For real?
∮ 哦 希德 ∮
∮ Oh, Oh, Sid ∮
∮ 希德 宝贝 ∮
∮ Sid, baby ∮
∮ 你让我感到真幸福 ∮
∮ You make me so happy ∮
∮ 哦 我从没想到我会成功 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would make it out ∮
∮ 走到今天 哦 我从来没想到 ∮
∮ And come this far Oh I never knew I ∮
∮ 预料到今天 我们走到了一起 ∮
∮ Would see the day we come together ∮
∮ 哦 这是前所未有的经历 ∮
∮ Oh, it's not like anything I've ever ∮
哇！
Whoa!
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你让我快乐 ∮
∮ You make me happy ∮
∮ 你让我欢笑 ∮
∮ You keep me laughing ∮
∮ 你让我的世界变得更美好 ∮
∮ You make my world a better place ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar my superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar my superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我们像强力胶一样粘在一起 ∮
∮ My super crew stick together like super glue ∮
∮ 我们的舞步 耶 ∮
∮ We got the moves like yeah ∮
∮ 我们闪耀光芒 ∮
∮ We're shining bright ∮
∮ 把你的手挥向蓝天 ∮
∮ Throw your hands up to the blue sky ∮
∮ 你 你让我快乐 ∮
∮ You You make me happy ∮
希德？
Sid?
我从来没有想过我会这样说
I never thought I'd say this,
但你在婚礼上做了巨大的贡献
but you did a great job on the wedding.
我欠你个大人情 伙计
I owe you bigtime, pal.
没错
You sure do.
这是你的账单 什么？
Here's my bill. What?
新娘的父亲要为婚礼买单
Father of the bride pays for the wedding.
我刚创立的传统
It's a tradition I just invented.
等一下 这太荒谬了
Wait a minute, this is ridiculous.
看你给花订的什么价格！
Look what you're charging for flowers!
花可不便宜
Flowers ain't cheap.
不！它们是免费的！我们在森林里！
No! They're free! We're in a forest!
这账单太离谱了！
This bill is outrageous!
火星
Mars.
这颗红色星球
The Red Planet.
寒冷 干燥 荒无人烟
Cold, dry, inhospitable to life.
但数十亿年前…
But billions and billions of years ago…
火星像这样
Mars looked like this.
有湖泊 河流 海洋…
There were lakes, rivers, oceans…
有着孕育生命的完美条件
the perfect conditions for life to form.
后来 发生了什么？
So, what happened?
为什么生命无法延续？
Why was life unable to take hold?
水去哪里了？
Where did the water go?
我们可能永远不会知道
We may never know.
∮ 哦 我从没想到我会成功 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would make it out ∮
∮ 走到今天 哦 我从没想到 ∮
∮ And come this far oh I never knew I ∮
∮ 预料到今天 我们走到了一起 ∮
∮ Would see the day we come together ∮
∮ 哦 这是前所未有的经历 ∮
∮ Oh, it's not like anything I've ever ∮
∮ 是的 宝贝 ∮
∮ Yeah, baby ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你让我快乐 ∮
∮ You make me happy ∮
∮ 你让我欢笑 ∮
∮ You keep me laughing ∮
∮ 你让我的世界变得更美好 ∮
∮ You make my world a better place ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你是我的彩虹 ∮
∮ You are my rainbow ∮
∮ 你把我的生活点缀得那么绚丽 ∮
∮ You color my day so bright ∮
∮ 我想和我的超级巨星永远待在一起 ∮
∮ I wanna stay forever with my superstar ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar My superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我的爱 我的爱 我的爱 ∮
∮ My love, my love, my love ∮
∮ 你照亮我内心 内心 ∮
∮ You're shining into my heart, heart ∮
∮ 哦 我从没想到我会拥有这一切 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would have it all ∮
∮ 会拥有这一切 ∮
∮ Would have it all ∮
∮ 哦 我从没想到会感到如此美妙 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would feel so good ∮
∮ 感到如此充实 ∮
∮ Would feel the full ∮
∮ 哦 我从没想到我会活在梦想中 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would live the dream ∮
∮ 如此 如此真实 ∮
∮ It's so, so real ∮
∮ 哦 我从没想到我会看到今天 ∮
∮ Oh I never knew I would see the day ∮
∮ 我们走到一起 ∮
∮ We'd come together ∮
∮ 哦 这是全所未有的体验 ∮
∮ Oh, it's not like anything I've ever felt before ∮
∮ 以前 以前 ∮
∮ Before, before ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你让我快乐 ∮
∮ You make me happy ∮
∮ 你让我欢笑 ∮
∮ You keep me laughing ∮
∮ 你让我的世界变得更美好 ∮
∮ You make my world a better place ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你是我的彩虹 ∮
∮ You are my rainbow ∮
∮ 你把我的生活点缀得那么绚丽 ∮
∮ You color my day so bright ∮
∮ 我想和我的超级巨星永远待在一起 ∮
∮ I wanna stay forever with my superstar ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar my superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright into my heart ∮
∮ 我的爱 我的爱 我的爱 ∮
∮ My love, my love, my love ∮
∮ 你照亮我内心 内心 ∮
∮ You're shining into my heart, heart ∮
∮ 你的光芒绚丽 绚丽 绚丽 绚丽 ∮
∮ You're shining bright, bright, bright, bright ∮
∮ 你的光芒如此绚丽 ∮
∮ You're shining so bright ∮
∮ 我的爱 我的爱 我的爱 ∮
∮ My love, my love, my love ∮
∮ 你照亮我内心 耶 耶 ∮
∮ You're shining into my heart Yeah, yeah ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你让我快乐 ∮
∮ You make me happy ∮
∮ 你让我欢笑 ∮
∮ You keep me laughing ∮
∮ 你让我的世界变得更美好 ∮
∮ You make my world a better place ∮
∮ 你 ∮
∮ You ∮
∮ 你是我的彩虹 ∮
∮ You are my rainbow ∮
∮ 你把我的生活点缀的那么绚丽 ∮
∮ You color my day so bright ∮
∮ 我想和我的超级巨星永远待在一起 ∮
∮ I wanna stay forever with my superstar ∮
∮ 我的超级巨星 ∮
∮ My superstar ∮
∮ 你光芒万丈 照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You shine so bright Into my heart ∮
∮ 你照亮我内心 ∮
∮ You're shining into my heart ∮
∮ 哦 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Ooh, Dream Weaver ∮
∮ 我相信你能陪我度过今夜 ∮
∮ I believe you can get me through the night ∮
∮ 哦 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Ooh, Dream Weaver ∮
∮ 我相信我们可以看到黎明 ∮
∮ I believe we can reach the morning light ∮
∮ 虽然黎明可能很快到来 ∮
∮ Though the dawn may be coming soon ∮
∮ 但时间还来得及 ∮
∮ There still may be some time ∮
∮ 带我飞向月球光亮的那一面 ∮
∮ Fly me away to the bright side of the moon ∮
∮ 和我在另一面相见 ∮
∮ And meet me on the other side ∮
∮ 哦 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Ooh, Dream Weaver ∮
∮ 我相信你能陪我度过今宵 ∮
∮ I believe you can get me through the night ∮
∮ 哦 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Ooh, Dream Weaver ∮
∮ 我相信我们可以看到黎明 ∮
∮ I believe we can reach the morning light ∮
∮ 筑梦者 ∮
∮ Dream Weaver ∮